# AURÉLIE JOSSERAND

Front-end developer

www.ajosserand.com

josserand.n.aurelie@gmail.com 🖸

linkedin.com/in/aurelie-josserand @

Pronouns: She / They (4)

405 500 7044 **(** 



#### **PROFILE**

Over the past ten years, I've built products for companies, businesses and government entities around the globe with a focus on design, usability, accessibility and inclusivity.

While the products I design have been in the built environment, the skills I have learned as an architect and designer are all applicable to front-end development. From working with multi-disciplinary teams, to iterating through design concepts and working with stakeholders, I am committed to meeting client expectations while creating great user experiences.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE**

University of Oklahoma Oklahoma, 2011-2012

#### **BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE**

Ecole Nationale Superieure d'Architecture France, 2007-2010

#### **LANGUAGES**

English - Fluent French - Native

# **OTHER QUALIFICATIONS**

Registered Architect EDAC Accredited LEED Accredited BD+C

#### **Green Card Holder**

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Codecademy - Front End Engineer Track

Winter 2021 to present

- Works to solve complex challenges with the utilization of modern web application development processes and standard methodologies.
- Designs, develops and tests responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessible webpages and apps using Javascript, CSS, Node.js, Mocha, React JS and Github.
- Built an interactive tip calculator app, a product launch countdown page and a web app for creating custom playlists using the Spotify API.

# Smithgroup, Washington, District of Columbia

2015 to present - Architect

- Leads system coordination on large scale projects involving multi-disciplinary teams of engineers and designers.
- Involved in all project phases from project pursuits to construction administration.
- Promotes the company brand through online and in person community activities and organization involvement.
- Engaged in various building types from museums and university buildings in Washington D.C, to hospital towers in China.

#### Miles Associates, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

2012 to 2015 - Project Coordinator

- Developed the company Website Design using Squarespace CMS.
- Led 3D visualizations efforts.
- Assisted project teams on construction documentation and project pursuits.

#### **AWARDS & LEADERSHIP**

### **Lead Panel Moderator**

Summer Leadership Summit 2019

# Guest Speaker

George Washington University, 2019

#### **Panel Speaker**

Summer Leadership Summit 2019

## **Next General Scholar**

Summer Leadership Summit 2018

#### **TOOLBOX**

Web Design	HTML5	GIT	3DSMAX
Responsive Design	CSS	Figma & XD	Lumion
3D Design	JavaScript	GreenSock	Sketchup
AR/VR	ReactJS	Google Workspace	Revit
SEO Best Practices	Mocha	Adobe Photoshop	Dynamo
Project Management	Nodes.js	Adobe Illustrator	AutoCAD